Just one sec .
Hasta El Fuego . Please hold .
Okay .
This way .
- See ya . - All right , see ya .
Here you are . Your server will be right with you .
- Hey , Jason . - Hey .
Hi . Do you know what you want ?
Yeah . Thanks .
So , how was it ?
It was great .
Hi !
- Another shot ? - Yeah , sure . Okay .
- Hi , hi , Reggie . Hello . - Laura , hi .
So nice to phone-meet you in this incredibly embarrassing way .
You know , no ... no problem .
- It 's fine . - This is what I get
for picking a trendy place with no sign out front , huh ?
Yeah , why do they do that here ?
I don 't know . I 've only been in the city for a few months .
Me too ! No way !
- Oh , wow . - Yeah .
Well , it 's a very cool restaurant .
- Is it on Hudson ? - Yes .
- Am I on Hudson ? - I don 't know .
I am not on Hudson . Shit .
I am now walking towards Hudson .
- Okay . - I am so , so sorry .
This is not the first impression I wanted to make
on a college professor .
Associate Professor , and it 's just Film Studies , so ...
you 're safe .
Film Studies ? That 's cool .
You say that , but try teaching a class on 20th-century slashers
to a heap of hungover 19-year-olds .
Slashers , huh ? What 's your favorite scary movie ?
Not that one .
So , why slashers ?
Well , I just ... You know , I think it 's interesting .
You can really examine the culture of the moment
by looking at the tropes of the time .
Like the masked killer , the final girl , the different rules :
Don 't split up . Don 't have sex .
- Don 't answer the phone . Yeah . - Exactly , exactly , exactly .
It 's all cliché . But out of those clichés
comes an opportunity for outsider art .
A voice for the voiceless , you might say .
Jesus Christ .
Yeah , I 'm more of a rom-com guy , to be honest .
- Okay , I think I 'm on Hudson . - Okay .
What color is the outside of the restaurant ?
I think it 's red .
I don 't see anything red .
I ... I could be wrong . Let me just ...
Let me go have a little look-see .
Okay . Thank you .
Yep , it 's definitely red .
Yeah , I 'm not seeing anything red here .
Sure you 're on Hudson ?
Crap , I 'm still a block over .
It looks like there 's an alley I can cut through .
Is the restaurant near an alley ?
Yes ! Yes . There is an alley .
Perfect . Okay . I 'm coming down the alley .
I don 't see you .
Wait . Really ? Are you sure ?
There are some dumpsters about halfway down .
I see them , but I don 't see you .
Yeah , I don 't see you , either .
This is creepy , right ?
A little bit .
20th-century slashers , huh ?
Yeah . Are you sure you 're walking towards Hudson ?
I 'm sure .
Oh , wait , I think I see you ! Can you wave ?
Can you see me ?
The person I 'm looking at isn 't waving .
They 're just staring at me .
Are you sure ?
Okay , this is weird .
Now they 're moving towards me .
Are you okay ?
Shit . He 's following me .
I don 't ... I don 't see anybody .
Holy shit , he 's after me !
Where are you ?
- He 's got a knife ! He 's got a knife ! - What ?
- What ? - And that 's not the worst part .
The worst part is ...
you teach a class about slashers
and you still walked into a dark alley . Alone .
Okay , that 's not funny .
No .
It 's not .
Now I see something red .
Oh , hey . Tara !
Jason .
Are you and Greg gonna come to the OKB party ?
If he finishes his Spanish project in time , yes , we will .
Is your sister coming ?
No , Sam wouldn 't be caught dead at a frat party .
There 's a first time for everything .
Not tonight , though .
Can 't convince her ?
That 's not my problem , that 's yours .
Save me a drink !
All right . I 'll see you .
Honey , I 'm home !
Greg ?
I 'm sorry , okay ? I ...
I just got massive blue balls , and I had to practice .
Please don 't be mad . How mad are you ?
I 'm not mad , Jason .
Dude . We said we wouldn 't use the voice on each other .
We said a lot of things .
This is Greg , right ?
Who else would it be ?
Where are you ? I want to tell you about it .
Oh , by the way ...
we should go to that frat party . Tara 's going .
What was it like ?
Not on the phone , man .
And , seriously , turn off the fucking voice modulator !
I 'm just trying to get the voice right .
You got to have your practice , I get mine .
Whatever .
Just tell me what it felt like .
Then maybe I 'll come out .
Dude , I know you 're not here .
Humor me .
All right , fine .
It was even better than we ever could have imagined .
I mean , when the knife went in her , it 's like she wasn 't human anymore .
Just an animal .
And every time it went in
she was less and less human .
And then ...
she was just meat .
But she wasn 't just meat , Jason .
She was a person . Our film professor .
Yeah , well ...
fuck her .
She gave me a C-minus on my giallo paper .
Is that why you killed her ? Because of the C-minus ?
Who 's next , your grade-school vice principal ?
You know who 's next . Why are you being like this ?
Come on , Jason . How long have we known each other ?
You tell me .
Eight years .
We met in junior high . In Atlanta .
I just want you to tell me why you think you 're doing this .
In your words .
We 're finishing Richie 's film .
That 's right , by killing Sam and Tara .
Why are you fucking with me ?
Why won 't you tell me where you are ?
Why do you keep asking me that ? I already told you .
I 'm here .
Let 's play a game .
Oh , shit .
Do you know Warmer , Colder ?
Come on . Find me , then we 'll go and cut up the Carpenter sisters .
Are you using the fucking cameras ?
Yeah . The cameras .
And at the moment , you 're very , very cold .
All right , douchebag , let 's play .
Cold .
Heating up .
Warmer .
All right , you know what ? This is stupid .
I 'm gonna hang up now .
But you 're getting warmer .
Colder .
Warmer .
You 're on fire !
Oh , fuck !
Do you feel like an animal , Jason ?
Please , stop !
Like meat ?
But we have to finish the movie .
Who gives a fuck about movies ?
So how are the new meds treating you ?
Okay , I think .
Still not seeing anyone I shouldn 't be .
What I 'm really worried about , though , is Tara .
What I 'm really worried about is you .
You 've been coming here for six months now
and all we 've really spoken about is how your sister isn 't dealing with
whatever happened to both of you a year ago .
Now , you 've alluded to an abusive relationship
issues with your father ...
But every time I push you for specifics
you shut down .
I have trust issues .
Okay .
If I 'm going to help you
I ... I need you to give me the details .
Okay .
My father was Billy Loomis .
He was a famous serial killer .
They made a movie about him .
Yeah . Certainly did .
Last year I found out that my boyfriend was also a serial killer
and only dating me because he idolized my father .
Him and his psycho girlfriend killed a bunch of people .
And when it got out that I 'm Billy 's daughter
this crazy rumor started online
that I orchestrated the whole thing and framed them .
Richie was my boyfriend .
But you didn 't .
- Of course not . - Okay .
He almost killed my sister and me
before I stopped him .
Okay , and how ...
how did you stop him ?
Well , I stabbed him 22 times and slit his throat .
Then I shot him in the head .
But that 's not why I 'm here .
Why are you here ?
Because ...
it felt right .
I ...
I think we 're done here .
What ? No , you said give you details .
- I 'm just ... - I 'm ... I 'm not equipped
to deal with this kind of thing .
Please , Dr. Stone .
I 'm asking for your help .
By law , I 'm required to report this to the authorities .
Report it ? Report what ?
I didn 't say I was gonna do anything .
Not explicitly , no .
You know what ?
Forget it .
You 're just like all the others .
Hey , you 've reached Tara . Why aren 't you texting me ?
You know you 're supposed to pick up when I call .
I got out of therapy early
so I was thinking maybe we cook dinner tonight .
If you want . I 'll see you soon .
Hey !
Tara ?
Quinn ?
Were we being too loud ?
Not at all . Have you seen Tara ?
Don 't be mad .
- Why would I be mad ? - Because you get mad .
Is that Paul ?
Who the fuck is Paul ?
Life , I have found , is about variety .
Okay .
- This one 's yours . - Thanks .
- Where 's Tara ? - She went
to the Omega Kappa Beta party .
I begged her not to go to that !
And we 've now arrived at mad .
Do you know if she at least took her Taser ?
I cannot speak to how heavily armed Tara is at this fraternity party .
Babe , are you coming back ?
- " Babe " ? - I don 't know .
Is Cute Boy shirtless again ?
Who 's Cute Boy , babe ?
Always you , sweetie .
You guys have been checking each other out for months .
Why don 't you just talk to him ?
Because that right there
is about all the romantic interaction I 'm ready for .
I 'm gonna go find Tara .
Okay .
- Be right back . - Bye .
Damn .
- What up , man ? - Do you know
- where I can get another beer ? - Hey , who 's drinkin ' ?
Hey , guys ! Oh , my God , Lou ! How are you ?
It doesn 't bother you ?
I mean , being at a house party
after you were almost brutally murdered at a house party ?
No , I think of it like being struck by lightning .
The odds of it happening twice to the same person are extremely low .
Guess I should stay close to you then .
- Shit , I 'm sorry . - Watch out .
Hi .
How are you doing , T ?
You 're lying .
No , last one 's kicked .
We got some hard stuff in the kitchen , though .
Frankie .
Tara .
Lead the way .
You Omega Beta Zeta ?
No , not yet . But I might rush it .
Oh , freshman . Right on !
Where from ?
Michigan .
All right .
You know what ?
I got a bottle of Fireball up in my room .
Fuck it . Yeah , go .
Oh , I don 't love that .
Hey ! You want to call it a night ?
No ...
I think that I 'm actually still gonna hang
but you guys don 't have to wait for me .
Don 't worry . I 'll take care of her . I 'm Frankie .
And I 'm spectacularly uninterested in knowing anything about you .
No , dude , Anika , I 'm not that bad .
But I appreciate you looking out for me .
See it in your face .
Closer . Closer .
All right , all right , hey , cheers , man , to the dynamic duo
of Hortense Tower , third floor , room 315 .
Yeah .
- Yeah . - Oh , man .
Time to start making moves .
Yeah . Get you out there . Introduce you to some girls !
What about her ?
She 's gorgeous .
- Great , ask her out . - No , I can 't
- just go up and ask ... - Ask her out ... ask her out .
- Shut up ! - You gotta have confidence .
Plus , look at you , man ! You 're a snack !
Practically an entire meal all on your own .
- Really ? - Yeah . You 're Ethan Landry .
Hey , excuse me !
- Chad . - Howdy . How you doing ?
My friend here , he 's a snack , right ?
What , what did that mean ?
Oh , it 's good , it 's good .
- What ? - It 's not bad .
There 's room for improvement !
Hey , big guy , you 're needed .
See ya .
Aren 't you that girl involved in that Stab shit in California last year ?
No . That 's a different pirate .
Hey , partner !
Tara 's good down here .
Sorry , bro , I didn 't catch that .
Yeah , you did .
No , Chad .
- It 's fine . I want to . - Yeah , yeah
see , Chad ?
- It 's okay . - She wants to .
Come on .
How ' bout you get your fucking hands off her ?
- What , you got a fuckin ' problem ? - Get the fuck off me !
- Guys ! Guys ! - Why are you ... Get the fuck off !
- Hey ! Who are you , huh ? - Fuck you !
- Risky Business ? You got a fuck ... - Stop ! Stop ! Stop !
Guys ! Guys ! Guys !
Sorry to interrupt . I 'm just gonna tase you in the balls real quick .
Don 't ever lay hands on my sister .
You fucking bitch !
- Fuck you ! - Sam .
Are you fucking kidding me ?
You 're stalking me now ?
Holy shit , it 's that psycho girl !
That 's her ?
Get the ice !
Tara . Will you stop ?
I cannot believe you did that ! You embarrassed me .
That guy was a dick . He was gonna take advantage of you .
- So ? - So ?
If I want to hook up with an asshole , that 's my decision !
- It 's my decision . - Okay .
It 's not about you . I mean , you 're out of my life for five years
and then you can 't leave me alone for five minutes .
Because you 're not dealing with what happened to us .
Have you even gone to see the counselor once ?
- No , I 'm not going to . - Why not ?
Because I 'm uninterested in living in the past like you are .
- What 's that supposed to mean ? - Hey , guys .
- Come on . - It means I 'm not gonna let
what happened to us for three days
define the rest of my life .
So you 're just gonna pretend it never happened .
What are you doing here , Sam ?
In New York .
You 're working two shitty jobs to help with rent , whatever
but what 's your plan ?
I know what I 'm gonna do .
Okay ? ' Cause I 'm gonna keep going to college
I 'm gonna get my degree , and I 'm gonna live my life .
My life .
Okay ? I know .
You just followed me here , and you won 't let me out of your sight .
I 'm just trying to look out for you .
I ...
I know .
I know you are .
You can 't do it for the rest of my life , though .
You have to let me go .
Hey !
- Hey , yo , yo . - Murderer !
What the fuck is wrong with you , bitch ?
- Sam , Sam , stand back ! - You got a problem with me ?
- You guys should stay away from her . - Knock it off !
She knows what she did .
- I didn 't fucking do anything ! - Go fucking stalk
- somebody else ! - Sure , bitch .
- Walk away ! - Again ?
- I 'm so sick of this shit . - Hey , calm down .
Fuck . It 's like the world 's
- gone insane . - Come on .
Hey , I ... I have tissues if you want tissues .
I have , like , three tissues .
Hey .
I 'm sorry I told Sam where you went .
It 's fine . I just ...
She 's all the way up my ass
like usual .
I know what it 's like when they hold on too tight .
After we ...
lost my brother ...
my dad wouldn 't leave me alone .
He even transferred to the NYPD when I got into college , so ...
Stalker much ?
I 'm gonna go , let you guys ... chat .
Thank you . You can ...
go back to your dorm . I 'm pretty sure the fighting is done for the day .
That 's too bad .
I was actually looking forward to getting some shots in while I can .
- Oh , yeah ? - Yeah .
Bring it .
Thank you
for not letting me go up those stairs .
Yeah , I don 't know , I think I was just more messed up than I realized .
Survivors got to stick together .
And besides , you can do a lot better than Date Rape Frankie .
Tara , you 're ...
I think you 're really special .
I 'm not messed up anymore .
Just so you know .
Okay .
I forgot my phone .
Did I cock-block you ?
- What did you just say ? - I cock-blocked you .
- No . - I cock-blocked you , didn 't I ?
- Please ... - Immediate no .
- Stop saying the word " cock . " - I totally ...
- All right . - What did you ...
- What did you need ? - My phone .
- So ... - Don 't ever enter
- a room like that again . - I won 't .
- Yeah . No , it was rude . - I 'm gonna go .
But get some rest , get sober
and please don 't kill your sister , okay ? She loves you very much .
- Bye . - Good night !
Bye-bye .
- Quinn ... - I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry .
Fuck .
Careful .
Someone might see us .
You always say the most romantic things .
- Danny . - What ?
Can I help it if my kink is " woman who 's ashamed to be seen with me " ?
Come on . You know it 's not that . I 'm just ...
- not ready for ... - I know , I know
for your sister and your friends
to know that you enjoy physical contact with another human being .
I get it , I do . Your secret is safe with me .
A little thing , just no ... It 's not a big deal ...
I just can 't help but notice that you 're covered in Cherry Coke .
I 'm pretty sure it 's Diet Cherry Coke , actually .
What , you don 't like it ?
No , I love it ! I do .
It 's a very sensual , aromatic choice .
Was that another conspiracy nut ?
Being famous isn 't all it 's cracked up to be .
And Tara 's pissed at me . Again .
She says she wants me to let her go .
Yeah , family can be rough .
Sam !
Get up here right now !
I 'm standing in front of
- the apartment building - What 's going on ?
Where the mutilated bodies of
- two Blackmore University students - Cute Boy . Nice .
Were discovered .
Their names have just been released by police .
Jason Carvey
- and Greg Bruckner . - Holy shit
that 's that chode from our Film Studies class !
- The one obsessed with Argento . - Also found at the scene
were various Ghostface costumes a character popularized
by the Stab movie franchise . Now this , of course , is not
- Pack a bag . We leave in ten . - the first time that the Ghostface
- Sam ! Wait , Sam ! - costume has been associated
- We 're getting out of the city . - with a brutal killing .
- What ? - Thank you very much
suspicious new guy , but I think we got it from here .
- Have a good night . Get home safe . - Are you serious ?
- Go ... go . - Come on .
Sam !
Sam , wait , hold ...
- Hold on . - Come on .
No , wait , let 's talk about this for a second .
Because this , this might not have anything to do with us .
- Are you serious ? - It 's a big city !
It 's Halloween . Everybody 's wearing masks !
- You don 't know . - Tara , Tara
this isn 't a coincidence .
You knew him !
- Barely . - Chad , Mindy , back me up .
I mean , it is a little bit ...
Close to home .
See ?
Quinn , your dad 's a cop , right ?
Can you call him and find out what 's going on ?
Before you make the unilateral decision
to abandon my college education and flee the fucking state !
- I 'm calling him now . - Thank you .
Who is it ?
Why did everyone just freak out when her phone rang ?
You got to keep up , my dude .
Sam ?
My dad wants to talk to you .
Mr. Bailey , hi .
Hey , Sam .
I was actually just about to call you .
Well , my sister thinks I 'm probably overreacting .
No , unfortunately , you 're not .
What do you mean ? What 's going on ?
I 'm afraid I need you to come down to the station .
Sam , slow down .
Tara , no . Get back inside , lock the door .
Are you serious ? Now you don 't want to stick together ?
Fine .
What the fuck ?
I never deleted his contact .
- This is coming from his number . - Don 't pick that up .
Just let it ring .
Sam .
- Who is this ? - Hello , Samantha .
Did you miss me ?
I want you to think long and hard
about whether you really want to do this .
Because the last two people that fucked with us ended up dead .
You should be thanking me , Sam .
Jason and Greg were gonna kill you and your sister .
I gutted them before they had the chance .
So what ?
You 're protecting us now ?
Not quite .
I 'm going to show the world who you really are :
A liar and a killer .
I 'm going to punish you , Sam .
You shouldn 't believe everything you read on the Internet , asshole .
Don 't be cute . You 're gonna pay for what you did .
And I 'm not gonna stop until I butcher you .
You and anyone who gets between us .
You and Tara better watch your backs .
You better watch yours .
No !
Come on ! Run !
Come on !
Help ! Please !
In there !
Please ! Please help us !
- We were just attacked . - Please call 911 !
- There 's a fucking line here , girls . - There 's a man out there
and he 's trying to kill us ! I 'm telling you sir , just ...
You got a problem here , guy ?
Hey !
- Go out the back ! - Thank you !
Fuck , it 's locked .
Keys ! We need your keys !
- Look out ! - Watch out ! Watch out ! Watch out !
Wait ... wait ! No ... no !
Run !
Go ! Run !
Let 's go !
- I 'm goin ' around back . - Stay back there , ma 'am .
This was found next to the body at the apartment crime scene .
DNA says that it belonged to someone named Richie Kirsch .
Does that ring a bell ?
We 're familiar with him .
But the one that attacked us had a different mask on .
It was kind of more beat up . Like it was older .
I got to ask ...
do you have alibis for earlier tonight ?
I was at a party with my friends .
I was at my therapist 's .
I can give you his information . You can call to check if you want .
And then I met Tara at that party where I tased someone .
Unrelated .
Was that before or after this happened ?
- Murderer ! - What the fuck
- is wrong with you , bitch ? - Okay , Sam , Sam , stand back !
You got a problem with me ?
Before .
The point is , we were with people all night .
So , our roommate 's dad
just happened to pull our case .
That 'd be a crazy coincidence , right ?
- Yeah . - The detective who had the case
he offered it to me because it involves Quinn .
But I can totally give it back if you 're uncomfortable .
It 's up to you .
It 's fine .
So if the man who attacked you did steal your license
and plant it next to the body ...
it 'd probably be somebody close to you .
How long have you known your friends ?
Well , we moved here with Mindy and Chad
for summer semester like six months ago . So ...
Quinn , Ethan , Anika , all since then .
I think I can vouch for Quinn
so that 's one less we have to worry about .
Do either of you have anyone that might want to target you ?
Not anyone who 's still alive .
Yikes .
FBI 's here , claiming jurisdiction .
Where are they ?
Can I help you ?
Special Agent Kirby Reed , FBI . I work out of the Atlanta office .
Oh . You lost ?
Your two vics were residents of my city
before they moved here for college .
I have been investigating their online activity
for the past few months .
Wow . Why ?
I take a special interest in Ghostface attacks .
- Kirby ? - Hey , Sam .
What ?
Tara .
You 're the FBI ?
You guys know each other ?
Yeah .
We went to Woodsboro High together .
She was a senior when I was a freshman .
We share a certain history , yeah .
Look , I 'm not trying to get into a jurisdictional pissing contest here
I just want to help .
I 'll show you mine , et cetera .
Thank you .
He left this mask at the bodega .
DNA traces of two individuals
Charlie Walker , Jill Roberts , both deceased .
The Ghostface killers of 2011 .
Charlie Walker gave me this .
Like I said , I take a special interest .
Is this the mask he was wearing when he attacked you ?
No .
So he 's leaving them on purpose .
Which means whoever 's doing this
is a student of the killers who came before .
Maybe he believes Sam is the latest in a long line .
Yeah , good luck with that .
We 're getting out of town .
I 'm sorry , that 's not possible .
You 're both persons of interest in a double homicide
so you 're not allowed to leave town . Sorry .
- Are you serious ? - He 's right .
- But if we work together ... - We 're going .
- Here they come . Here they come . - I 'm rolling .
Samantha , do you have an alibi for last night 's murders ?
Tara , do you feel safe around your sister ?
- Tara ! Tara ! - The last one ...
Gale Weathers , Channel 4 .
Do you ladies think you 're the reason
the Ghostface killer has come to the Big Apple ?
Nice try , sweetie , but I 've done this dance before .
- Stay away from us . - Samantha !
- Right here , please . - Are you still mad at me ?
You said you wouldn 't write a book about what happened .
And then you wrote a book about
- what happened . - Oh , come on .
Somebody was gonna write about it ! It 's what I do .
I heard you couldn 't sell the movie rights .
It 's ... It 's all about true-crime limited series these days .
After everything we went through together .
What would Dewey think ?
- That 's a low blow . - So was your book .
You called me " unstable " and a " born killer " .
That 's taken out of context .
That 's literally a quote .
You don 't think what you wrote has something to do
with what 's happening to us ?
Come on .
Hey , I talked to Sidney .
She 's not coming here , is she ?
No .
She sends her love , but she 's taking Mark and the kids someplace safe .
She deserves to have her happy ending .
On that much , we agree .
Hey , I want to catch this fucker as much as you do !
Maybe .
Or maybe you 're just afraid that without Ghostface in your life
you 're gonna fade away .
You fools ! You 're in danger !
Can 't you see ? They 're after you ! They 're after all of us !
Our wives , our children , everyone !
They 're here already ! You 're next !
You 're next ! You 're next !
Who is it ?
You 're a day early for trick-or-treating , you know .
Yo , get me one !
Good , I 'll see you in there !
Come by our booth ! Free doughnuts !
A rumor !
Okay , nerds , listen up !
As terrifying as this all is
I 'm actually glad I get a chance to redeem myself
for not calling the killers last time .
- Yep . - It 's fine . Okay .
The way I see it , someone is out to make a sequel to the requel .
What 's a requel ?
You 're beautiful , sweetie . Let 's hold questions to the end .
Stab 1 took place in Woodsboro .
Stab 2 took place in college .
So we think that the killer is trying to copy the movies ?
That is one possibility .
Heroes now in college : Check .
Suspicious new characters brought in to round out the suspect list
and / or body count :
- Check , check and check . - I don 't like this .
- But it can 't just be about Stab 2 . - Why not ?
It would make sense if this were just a sequel .
But we 're not in a sequel , because nobody just makes sequels anymore .
We 're in a franchise !
And there are certain rules to a continuing franchise .
I had a feeling .
Rule one :
Everything is bigger than last time .
Bigger budget , bigger cast , bigger body count .
Longer chases , shoot-outs , beheadings .
You got to top what came before to keep people coming back .
- Beheadings ? - Beheadings .
Rule two : Whatever happened last time , expect the opposite .
Franchises only survive by subverting expectations .
If the killers last time were whiny snowflake film nerds
with Letterboxd accounts instead of personalities
you can bet the opposite will be true here .
And rule three : No one is safe .
Legacy characters ? Cannon fodder at this point .
Usually brought back only to be killed off
in some cheap bid for nostalgia .
It 's not looking too good for Gale and Kirby .
Oh , and that 's not even the worst part !
This is the part where she tells us the worst part .
The worst part is
franchises are just continuing episodic installments
designed to boost an IP .
Which means main characters are completely expendable now , too .
Laurie Strode , Nancy Thompson , Ellen Ripley
Sally Hardesty , Jigsaw , Tony Stark , James Bond ...
I mean , even Luke Skywalker ! All died so their franchises could live on .
That means it 's not just the friend group .
Any of us could go at any time
especially Sam and Tara .
- Wait , any of us ? - Yeah .
- Am I in the friend group ? - Yeah .
Am I one of the targets ? Am ...
Am I gonna die a virgin ?
That was a weird overshare .
But it brings us to our current suspects :
Ethan . The shy , dorky guy
who no one suspects because he 's so shy and dorky .
Okay , wait . Why am I on the suspect list ?
Because I 'm randomly Chad 's roommate ?
Roommate lotteries can be juked .
You could have fixed it to get next to us .
Quinn .
The slutty roommate . A horror movie classic .
" Sex positive , " but thank you ?
How did you come to live with Sam and Tara ?
I answered their ad online .
Okay , say no more . You 've already implicated yourself enough .
It was an anonymous ad , Mindy .
And you know we vetted her . Plus her dad is a cop .
And that makes it more likely that she 's the killer
because having a cop dad is a great cover .
Do you not remember how these movies work , Tara ?
Is she always like this ?
And finally , Anika .
Never trust the love interest .
Okay ! So , we have our rules and we have our suspects .
But wait . What about you guys ?
I mean , I think it 's pretty safe to rule out the four of us
who went through this last year in Woodsboro .
Agreed .
Not agreed . What if the trauma you all went through
caused one or more of you to snap ?
Yeah , or the fame you got from the killings
made you thirsty for more .
I mean , let 's be honest here
some of the theories online about Sam are ...
Don 't you fucking dare .
Okay , she 's right , though .
I mean , face facts
if we 're all suspects , you 're all suspects .
Remember Samantha Carpenter 's alibi , the therapist ?
He was stabbed to death . Through the nose .
Through the nose . How messed up is that ?
It 's pretty messed up .
He turned her in for making threatening remarks , ended up dead .
And guess which patient 's notes were stolen ?
So Sam kills her own alibi and steals her own session notes ?
Maybe .
Another mask was found at the scene .
It 's a DNA match for Roman Bridger .
The Ghostface who was directing Stab 3 .
It 's like he 's leaving us real-life franchise Easter eggs .
Like dropping the killers ' masks in reverse .
Almost like he 's counting down to something .
What happens when he gets to one ?
So we 've had nine Ghostface killers so far .
Nine . But I thought in the movies ...
Forget about the movies . The movies don 't matter .
Look . Last year was Amber Freeman and Richie Kirsch
whose masks we found at the first crime scene
along with the bodies of two film students who killed their professor
earlier that same night .
Then it was Jill Roberts and Charlie Walker , theirs at the bodega .
Roman Bridger was the only single Ghostface .
Kudos to him for ambition .
His mask was found at the shrink 's .
Which just leaves Mickey Altieri , Nancy Loomis , Stu Macher ...
and Billy Loomis . Number one .
And the father of our chief suspect .
Yeah , well , whoever 's doing this is leading us back to Sam .
I will check in later .
And tell your daughter to stay sharp .
Proximity to the Carpenters is proximity to Ghostface .
Hey , Jack ? Would you call the Atlanta field office ?
Dig up what you can on Agent Reed .
I think you should get out of the city .
You know , considering what happened to you last time .
I wouldn 't blame you if ...
you wanted to go .
That 's very thoughtful of you , but ...
I don 't think I 'm going anywhere .
- Will you two just make out already ? - Mindy .
- That is so inappropriate , dude . - Oh , whatever .
Get it over with !
- Here you go . - Sam ?
Yep ?
We do not have to stay here .
Well , too bad . I insist . Safety in numbers .
This 'll be so fun . A little slumber party with the Core Four !
- " Core Four " ? - Yeah .
- Did you just give us a nickname ? - I sure did .
We 've been through a lot together , and it 's a pretty cool nickname .
- That 's debatable . - It 's extremely debatable .
You can 't just give yourself a nickname , dingus .
Of course I can , dingus , because I just did .
- Core Four , up top ! - No .
- Down low . - Get that away from me .
- Please , for the love of God . - Don 't do it .
You know , I would actually like
- a little more respect and support - Oh , my God .
From my fellow members of the Core Four
- next time I try . - You 're making it worse .
Guys ! What the hell ?
We 're hearing from sources inside the homicide division
that the prime suspect is none other than Samantha Carpenter
one of the survivors of the Woodsboro killings in 2022
seen here attacking a woman on the street last night .
♪ ♪ ♪ ♪ is wrong with you ?
- Sam , stand back ! - You got a problem with me ?
- Knock it off ! - You guys should stay away from her .
She knows what she did .
In the wake of the Woodsboro tragedy last year , rumors sprouted online
that Carpenter was actually responsible for the killings
blaming the crimes on her boyfriend , Richie Kirsch
and teen Amber Free ...
I know you 're not a fan of the way that I 've been handling things
and that I 've been giving you a really hard time .
But I can say that ...
none of us can relate to what you are experiencing .
And I 'm really , really sorry that you have to do that alone .
It 's not your fault .
And I know I shouldn 't care what people think .
It just sucks being this hated .
Hey . Hey . Just a reminder
not a single person in this room hates you .
Okay ? We have all been through some fucked-up stuff
and we are coping with it differently .
But we moved here together for one very specific reason .
We are a team .
We are ...
- the Core Fucking Four . - Thank you very much .
- That 's absolutely right . - I hate myself .
- That 's all . That 's - You said it .
- What I 'm talking about . - I am so sorry .
It 's the Core Four .
- Say it . - No , I 'm not gonna say it . Not now .
- I mean , yes , we 're a team , but ... - Core Four . Exactly .
- It 's got a nice ring to it . - Come on , say it .
I 've been sleeping with Cute Boy from across the hall .
- I fucking knew it ! - Boom !
I knew it , I knew it , I knew it .
- Amazing . Good . - You called it .
I knew it from the day you had that hickey .
Sales of the Ghostface Halloween mask across the tri-state area
in the last 24 hours have gone through the roof .
- I 've got my mask . What about you ? - You know it .
- It 's gonna be one spooky Halloween . - I 'll say .
Now let 's get over to Guy for a look at our weather .
Yeah , I know she 's my roommate , but you 're , like , the police .
Yo .
- No , I know . - Hey !
Fuck .
Hey , yeah . Wassup , bitch ?
I see you , motherfucker !
Let 's go !
Sam ! Samantha !
I feel like we should high five or something .
The Core Four high five
- may we , please ? - Don 't call it that
- but we 'll do the high five . - But it 's kinda cute .
- Come on . - Keep going with it .
- That 's gross . - Sam !
- I feel like that was really ... - Samantha !
Sam , what the fuck ?
She 's really freaked out and paranoid .
- Babe , you gonna join me ? - Hang on .
No . And don 't use my good face wash . It 's pH-balanced for women .
Pick up your phone , baby .
- No , I 'm not gonna do it again . - Say , listen .
- That was really ... - No way .
- Is that him ? Is that him ? - Is that him right now !
- Yes , yes , yes ! - No , no , no , give it .
- No , Tara . No . Not right now . - Hey , so what are your intentions ?
Yeah , that 's right .
It 's fine . I 'll call him back .
- Okay . Okay . - Poor guy .
It 's fine .
Oh , my God , Quinn and her gentleman caller
are back at it again .
- She 's getting it , too ? Okay . - That 's right .
Help ! Stop !
No , Tara , wait , wait !
Run .
- Oh , my God . - Come on !
Guys , come on !
Oh , fuck .
Mindy ! Stay the fuck back !
No !
Hey !
Wait , Chad !
- They 're still up there . - Shit !
Come on , come on !
Fuck .
Sam !
- Do you have the keys ? - Fuck ! No , I left them inside !
Mindy , bathroom door . Hurry !
Oh , fuck ! That guy 's dead .
Oh , shit .
Oh , fuck .
Hey !
Shit .
Don 't worry , I got you .
Are you fucking kidding me ?
You have a better idea ?
Fuck . No .
You have to come one at a time .
Okay . You two go first .
- Mindy ! Mindy ! - What ? No .
Someone needs to hold the door . I 'll send Anika next . Go !
Sam , come on . Eyes on me , baby .
Keep your eyes on me .
Go !
Oh , shit .
- Oh , my God . - I got you , baby , I got you .
- Baby , come on ! - Okay .
- Come on ! - It won 't hold me .
- Okay . - It ain 't going anywhere .
It 's gonna hold you , I promise .
Danny .
Sam , I got you .
- You ain 't going nowhere . Let 's go . - Go , Sam .
She 's losing a lot of blood !
Say something more positive !
Eyes on me , Sam . Come on , baby .
Come on . Come on , baby . I got you .
Come on , I got you .
Okay .
- Come on ! - Let 's go !
- Come on , Mindy ! - Yo , let 's go , we got to move !
Anika , come on !
- Come on . - Anika !
- Let 's go ! Come on ! - Come on .
Okay , you have to go first .
- You 're gonna go first . Honey . - I can 't .
Look at me . You have to go .
- You have to go . - No , Mindy , no !
I 'll be right behind you , I promise .
- Come on ! - Let 's go !
Mindy , come on ! You got to get over here now !
Let 's go !
- We got you . - That 's it . Mindy .
- Slow and steady . - Come on . We got you .
Oh , God .
- Let 's go ! Step by step ! - Come on !
- Let 's make moves ! - Come on , baby !
- You gotta go ! - Mindy , you need to get over here
- right now ! - That 's it . That 's it .
- She 's coming right behind you . - That 's it .
- Anika 's coming right behind you . - That 's exactly it .
Okay , we got you .
Anika , come on !
- Come on , Anika ! - Go !
Come on ! You can do it !
Come on , come on , Anika !
- Oh , God ! I can 't do it . - Yes , you can !
I can 't do it .
- Don 't look down ! - Look at me !
- Let 's go ! - You can do it !
- Come on ! - That 's it . You 're doing good .
What ?
Anika , you have to move right now !
You have to move !
Move ... move !
No , God ! Please , no !
Anika , you got to move !
No !
Keep going , Anika !
You have to make it !
Baby , I don 't want to die !
No , Anika !
Anika , give me your hand .
Go ! I got you ! I got you !
Yes ! Yes !
Hey . You okay ?
This isn 't your fault , Sam .
But it is .
Someone took our knives
so we couldn 't fight back .
I don 't know who I can trust .
Then don 't trust anyone . Not your friends . Not me .
Not anyone .
I have a few more questions for you .
Just this way , Danny .
All right , come on , Mike .
Okay , yeah . I think this is good .
Just get right up to the tape here .
Chad .
- Where were you ? - What ? When ?
- Last night ! - What ? I had Econ . You know this .
Bullshit , man ! You disappear , and my sister almost gets killed !
Dude , I was in a study hall with a hundred other people .
You can ask any of them .
Fuck , man .
Oh , my God .
- Who ? - Anika and Quinn .
Mindy , I 'm so sorry .
Step the fuck back .
You 're at the top of my list .
I had Econ !
Go right ahead , sir .
I 'm gonna be right back .
I 'm really sorry about Quinn .
Thank you .
Both my kids are gone .
My whole family
is gone .
They took me off the case .
But I 'm not gonna stop until I find him .
You fuck with my family ...
you die .
Agreed .
Hey , are you okay ? I came as soon as I heard .
Gale , I swear to God ...
Truce , okay ? I 'm here for whatever you need .
Okay . Nice try .
Really , I am .
Okay , fine . Off the record , okay ?
Okay . Thank you .
I 'm sorry I punched you .
No , you 're not .
I 'm not .
You 're the cop , right ?
I did some digging on your first two victims and I found something .
I know where the masks are coming from .
- Show me . - Ladies .
Kirby ?
- Gale . - She 's with the FBI .
She 's a child .
When did they start letting children into the FBI ?
- I 'm 30 . - Well , you look like a zygote .
I have a gun , Gale .
Okay , fine . You 're gonna want to see this , too .
Jason and Greg were little Atlanta rich boys .
Apparently , they used fake names to rent this place .
How did you find it ?
It 's called " investigative journalism " for a reason .
How didn 't you find it ? Weren 't you tracking them ?
I went through their financial records
dozens of times .
This was not in any of them . Doesn 't make sense .
Don 't worry . I 'm just really good at my job . You 'll get there .
What is this place ?
What 's with all the security ?
It 's a movie theater .
It 's not just a theater .
It 's a shrine .
They 've got the whole goddamn franchise .
Chad ?
This was Uncle Randy 's .
They 've got everything .
- Is that ... - The knife I was stabbed with .
You all have been through so much .
Who drew all these ?
Dewey .
Hey , how 'd they get all this stuff ?
Isn 't this evidence ?
Well , cops like money , and evidence can get lost pretty easily .
Present company excluded , of course .
Why am I here exactly ?
My alibi checks out .
So I can keep an eye on you , roomie .
The killer must have found this place before he murdered Jason and Greg .
And then he took the masks off the mannequins .
All nine , from Stu and Billy to Amber and Richie .
Hot damn !
How fucking cool is this place ?
Fuck , no .
Fuck , yes .
Come on , Sam , you got to be excited to get our murder on again . Together .
Billy and Sam . Team Loomis .
Get ready to slice up more motherfuckers .
What are you doing ?
I don 't know .
So
Somebody killed these chucklefucks and ...
took over ?
Someone who believes that Sam masterminded Woodsboro .
If this were a normal Stab movie , this would be the killer 's lair .
Which means this isn 't a normal Stab movie .
The TV that killed Stu Macher .
If you believe he 's dead .
I hear you 're a horror fan .
It 's been said .
Best Nightmare on Elm Street ?
- The original . - The original .
Best Friday the 13th ?
- Part II . - The Final Chapter .
Had a crush on Corey Feldman .
Okay . Respect .
Psycho II is ...
- underrated . - Underrated .
Candyman . The original or requel ?
- Both . - Both .
Okay . Okay .
Game recognize game .
You okay ?
Sam , when do I get to be a normal person again ?
I don 't know .
I don 't want to be a part of this .
I don 't want to be a part of some stupid legacy because I 'm ...
Because of me .
I 'm sorry .
Just drop it , Sam .
Tara .
I got her .
That seemed intense .
Ever since I came back into her life , I 've just ...
made a mess of it .
Hey .
Where 's your mother in all this ?
She cut me off when I told Tara about Billy .
Then Tara cut her off because she wouldn 't talk to me , so ...
now neither of us have a mother .
I 'm sorry to say this , but fuck her .
My parents sucked , too .
But you can still make your own family .
Even if it 's just with one person .
And if you lose that one person ?
You just keep going .
And maybe you find another loner , and you look after each other .
How 'd you get past what happened to you ?
I almost died after I was stabbed .
Technically , I did die .
For four minutes .
When I recovered ...
I got mad .
I didn 't want to spend the rest of my life being afraid of monsters .
I wanted the monsters to be afraid of me .
I like that .
Sorry to interrupt .
Think I might have an idea about how to turn the tables on this creep .
Yeah . We 're in .
Sorry , Gale . No press allowed .
Police business . I 'm good at my job , too .
You should have stayed with the others .
That 's not gonna happen .
There 's no point in both of us putting ourselves at risk .
I 'm not .
I 'm your backup .
So we 're really doing the phone tracing thing
that never works in the movies .
It 'll be all , " Keep him talking , Sam .
Two more minutes , I 've almost got him . "
And then he hangs up just before we can get a lock .
I can trace a call in under 15 seconds .
Well , you 've got them out there as bait .
Because the killer usually calls from somewhere nearby .
And you think they 're safe because
it 's broad daylight in a public place ?
Look , I am here , okay ? And so is Bailey .
This is exactly how our Uncle Randy died .
Broad daylight . Public place .
Yanked into a van . Stab , stab , stab . No more Randy .
Hey , Sam ?
Stay frosty out there , okay ?
We 're good .
You 're gonna die , you know .
No , you 're gonna die , Samantha !
Choking on your own blood while I hack up your sister .
Unless we find you first .
For a mastermind , you 're not very bright .
Waiting for me to call
desperately hoping I 'm nearby so the police can grab me ?
But I 'm not nearby .
I 'm a step ahead .
Be seeing you , Samantha .
- Did you get it ? - Yep .
Geolocation coming through right now .
He 's on the Upper West Side .
He 's inside an apartment building , halfway across the city .
On West 96th ?
How did you know that ?
Gale .
" No press . "
Bitch , last time I saw you , you were in glee club .
Forgive me if I don 't trust you to keep them safe .
- Here you go , baby . - Thanks .
My friend Danny works on the Upper West Side .
He can get there quicker .
Yeah , or he could finish her off . Is it possible he 's the killer ?
Fuck . We have to get there now .
It 's 50 blocks away . We don 't even know if it 's true . Sam , wait !
- Take a minute . - We don 't have a minute .
Sam . You have to trust me , we got to make the right call .
- He 's already ... - Sam !
Get in .
What 's she doing ?
Hey . Hey , get out of my car !
What do you think you 're doing ? That 's an official vehicle ! Hey !
Should we use the sirens ?
Did you really think we gonna steal a police car and not use the sirens ?
- Do you even have a license ? - Fuck , yeah .
What are you doing ?
It 's a cop car ! You can 't steal a cop car !
That 'll be our food .
Hello ?
Not the food . It 's for you .
Who is it ?
May I ask who 's calling , please ?
He says it 's the killer .
- Hello ? - Hello , Gale .
Strange that you and I have never spoken on the phone .
This is long overdue .
I agree .
Call the police .
I figured after all these years
you 'd want an interview .
Well , you figured right .
So , what 's your motive this time ?
You angry at the movies or you just trying to stay relevant ?
I could ask you the same .
Don 't you know the legacy characters are disposable now ?
Nobody cares about last century 's heroes .
Then why bother with me at all ?
Call it nostalgia .
Or maybe you deserve to be punished
for all that money you made off the misery of others .
Maybe it 's time someone made a buck reporting your death .
You know you 're like the tenth guy to try this , right ?
And spoiler alert
it never works out for the dipshit in the mask .
Oh , but they certainly leave a mark before they go , don 't they ?
Richie and Amber managed to butcher Dewey .
Carved him up like a Christmas goose .
How does it feel to lose the only man who ever loved you ?
Fuck you !
How does it feel to know that you weren 't there for him at the end ?
Not there to give him comfort as he died screaming in his own guts .
You 're the one who 's gonna die screaming .
Maybe . But you won 't be around to see it .
You couldn 't stop what happened to Dewey .
Just like you 're not gonna be able to stop this .
Oh , God !
How 's that for nostalgia , fucker ?
You missed .
Sure I did .
You win . I 'm in the elevator heading for the ground floor .
Sure you are .
Maybe you did hit me . Maybe I 'm wounded .
Or maybe I 'm wearing a bulletproof vest .
That 's why I 'm gonna shoot you in the fucking head !
You would 've made a good killer , Gale .
Sidney never would 've made sense and Dewey was the fan favorite .
But you cracking under the pressure and turning into Ghostface
would 've been a great twist .
Keep talking , asshole .
Sure .
What do you want to talk about ?
You never got to be the leading lady , did you ?
It was always all about poor sweet Sidney
sucking up all the oxygen .
What did that leave you to be ?
The brains and the sex appeal .
Sorry about your boyfriend .
All those muscles didn 't help much .
They sure didn 't .
Can you hold , please ?
Fuck you !
Hey , fuckface !
Gale !
Oh , shit . Gale ?
Gale .
Sorry .
I 'm sorry .
I should 've known that he was gonna come after you .
I 'm so sorry .
He didn 't get me .
Tell Sidney
he never got me .
Gale ?
- Gale . - Gale .
Gale ? Please .
Out of the way !
- Out of the way ! - Gale !
- You got to move . Move ! - No .
No ! No ! No !
- Get them back , please . - Sam , please !
They need to move now .
Please step back .
Call it in .
Right away .
- Checking . - Come on , Gale .
Got a weak pulse . Get the backboard .
We need to move now .
Backboard ! Let 's move .
Hey .
I got here as fast as I could .
Did you ?
I 'm scared , you guys .
I really don 't want to get hurt again .
Neither do I.
I don 't want you getting hurt again , either .
I know . I know .
So what do we do now ?
Maybe he gets to win this time .
He wants to punish me .
Me .
So maybe I let him .
I 'll just give myself up .
If this is what I have to do
to keep you safe ...
- it 's worth it . - No
we 're not doing that , Sam .
All right . You went back to Woodsboro to protect me .
Every single day , you make the decision to protect me .
None of us would even be alive if it weren 't for you .
You have to let us protect you this time .
- No . - Yes .
We 're a team , remember ?
Actually ...
we 're a family .
Let 's go ! Core Four ! Come on .
- Core Four . - Come on .
- Core what ? - It 's an us thing .
He 's gonna keep coming after us .
Isn 't there somewhere that 's safe we could just hole up in ?
No , he 's just gonna keep finding us .
Great .
We could use that , though .
I 'm getting my ass chewed out for not dropping the case
and now you want me to do what ?
We want to lure him to a secure location
and trap him inside .
And then what ?
We execute him .
Are you gonna help us ?
Let 's kill the son of a bitch .
Now , I 'm stuck here , but Gale gave us the keycards to the theater .
It 's got heavy surveillance and security cameras
but we can use that against him .
I 'll tell Kirby to meet you there and I 'll join you as soon as I can .
- Got it . - And remember
travel in public .
The more people around you ,
the less chance he has to take a shot at you before you get there .
Is this even a good plan ?
You don 't have to come if you don 't want to .
So we just peel off and the killer picks us off one by one ?
No , thank you .
Let 's just get to the theater . Come on , in here .
Yes , because it 'll be much less scary at the serial killer movie theater .
Fuck .
Wait , hey , hey ! Chad !
Hey ! Fuck ! Chad !
Tara !
- Wait , where 's Mindy ? - Chad !
Sam ! Hey , Sam !
Mindy ! Mindy ! Mindy !
Let 's go . Let 's go .
- Oh , shit . - Fuck !
Fuck .
Oh , God . Get your Ghostface ass away from me , Ghostface .
Go away .
- Where 's Mindy ? - She missed the train .
I was gonna wait for her , but Cute Boy here dragged me on .
- I was trying to keep us together . - By pulling us apart ?
It 's okay . It 's okay .
It 's fine , she 's with Ethan .
She 'll meet us there .
This is a South Ferry bound local one train .
- Oh , shit . - The next stop is
79th Street .
How many stops do we have ?
Ten .
This is 79th Street .
This is a South Ferry bound local one train .
The next stop is 72nd Street .
The next stop is 79th Street .
Sorry !
Still nothing from Mindy .
This is 72nd Street .
Guys ?
The next stop is 66th Street , Lincoln Center .
Hey .
Fuck you .
This is a South Ferry bound local one train .
The next stop is 66th Street , Lincoln Center .
This is 66th Street , Lincoln Center .
As you exit , please be careful of the platform and the train .
Oh , shit .
Mindy ! Fuck !
Shit , shit . Mindy !
Fuck , fuck , that 's a lot of blood .
Help ! Somebody help !
Fuck . We got to get you out of here , okay ?
Damn it .
- Come on ! - Fuck !
Shit . Somebody call 911 !
- Oh , my God . - Are you okay ?
Yeah , I 'm so good .
You 're gonna be okay . You 're gonna be okay .
Goddamn it .
I got it wrong again .
- What the fuck ? - Help !
Yeah , we need medical assistance We 're at the 66th Street station .
Fuck this franchise .
Hey .
I talked to Bailey . I 've got everything set up .
Where are Mindy and Ethan ?
They 're five minutes behind us .
Let 's get you all inside .
- Not you . - What ?
Don 't trust anyone , remember ?
We don 't know you .
Not really .
You know me .
You 're not Woodsboro .
I 'm sorry .
It 's okay . It 's okay , I get it . I get it .
Be safe , okay ?
Okay ?
You , too .
Good call .
I cleared the whole place before you got here .
So , this is the only way in or out .
He steps in through the first door
both doors lock automatically , trapping him inside .
We turn it into a kill box .
- Weapons ? - One gun , and I hold onto it .
I am the only one with a badge here and that 's the way it 's gonna be .
We 're safe here .
I 'm gonna check in with Mindy .
See if they 're close .
Come on , come on .
Hey , you 've reached me . Leave a message .
You know you 're not safe here .
Whenever someone says , " We 're safe here , "
it means you 're not .
- Not now . - But you 're smarter than this , Sam .
Grab a weapon and clear this place yourself .
You know I 'm right .
Excellent choice .
My favorite .
Kirby ?
Kirby !
Hello ?
Get everyone out of there , Sam , you 're not safe .
I heard from the Atlanta field office .
They said Agent Reed 's been on a downward spiral
ever since the Woodsboro murders last year .
What are you talking about ?
They fired Kirby two months ago for being mentally unstable .
- What ? - She 's no longer with the FBI .
Listen , asshole .
No , you listen , you little bitch .
Hang up on me , I 'll gut you like a fish . Understand ?
What do you want ?
To see what your insides look like .
Oh , shit .
When was the last time anybody used this place ?
It 's so old .
I 'm sorry , you can ... you can have them .
- Take them . - Just ... No , I mean ...
If you want them , you have them .
- You think I want these ? - Kind of .
They 're a hundred years old .
Maybe that 's your thing .
I actually ...
It 's maybe embarrassing how long I 've wanted to do that .
Yeah , you should 've done that a lot sooner .
I know .
But you could also do it a lot more times .
Tara !
Tara , Tara , let 's go , let 's go . Come on ... come on !
Come on , come on , go , go , go !
It 's Kirby . She 's the killer .
No shit .
That 's locked .
- Come on . - Are we trapped ?
She made this whole theater a kill box . For us .
Hey , what about that ? There 's an exit door .
Maybe it leads to the roof or something ?
There 's only one way to find out . Let 's go , let 's go .
Bailey 's on the way , but ...
Oh , fuck !
Beheadings !
Tara ! Come on .
Smile for the camera , motherfucker !
This way ! Come on !
She should be running out the front door .
Get fucked !
Fuck this !
Tara , go ! Go !
No !
Chad !
Run .
Go .
Don 't go there . You 're starting to sound
- This way . Up here . Come on . - like a Wes Carpenter flick .
We 've got a long night ahead of us .
Everybody 's a suspect .
You 're not scared , are you ?
Oh , Sam !
It 's a lot scarier when there 's no motive , Sid .
Ready ?
I need you to be ready . Ready ?
Look at me .
I 'm ready .
Come on , motherfucker !
It 's okay !
Stay the fuck back !
We know it 's you , Kirby .
One of them knocked me out .
Kirby , stop !
Get away from the girls !
What are you doing ?
Did you kill Quinn ?
- Did you kill my daughter ? - Jesus Christ !
Whatever he 's been saying to you , don 't listen to him .
He 's probably the killer .
Behind you !
Great job .
Both of you .
- You ? - Yeah , of course me .
Frankly , I expected more from the two of you
after what you did to us .
What do you mean , " us " ?
Ta-da !
Mindy was right .
It was easy to juke the roommate lottery .
All I had to do to meet you
was room with a conceited , condescending alpha
literally named Chad .
Fuck , it felt good to kill him !
This was your grandmother 's , Sam .
Nancy Loomis ?
Really runs in your fucking family , doesn 't it ?
Speaking of family ...
- Wait for it . - My name 's not Ethan Landry
is it , Dad ?
" Dad " ?
Wait .
If it 's you two , that just leaves ...
Mindy ?
Hey , roomies .
You didn 't see that one coming , did you ?
Yeah , because you died !
Kind of didn 't , though .
It was a good way to get off the suspect list
stab Gale Weathers , stab Mindy on the train . That sort of thing .
Yep , and I just made sure I was first on the scene
so I could switch her body out with a fresh one .
A little fake blood , a prosthetic .
You 'd be amazed at what a grieving father can get away with .
I got Stu Macher 's mask .
He was my favorite .
Nice . That 's number three .
That 's two .
Which leaves ...
your father 's .
This is what we 've been counting down to , Sam .
I 'm gonna need you to put it on .
Fuck you !
You stay the fuck away from her !
Come on .
What ? What is this ?
You did this as a family ?
Hell yeah , bitch ! You should know better than anyone .
They 're still not getting it .
Look , I don 't know what you believe
but I didn 't commit those murders in Woodsboro . It wasn 't me !
We know that . Of course you didn 't .
What , do you think this is based on some bullshit conspiracy theory ?
Come on . Who do you think started the rumors about you in the first place ?
Do you know how easy it was
to turn Sam from the hero of Woodsboro into the villain ?
How easy it is to convince the world
to believe the worst in people rather than the best ?
Because it 's not enough to just kill someone these days .
You have to assassinate their character first .
So when Dad here " discovers " your horribly mutilated bodies ...
posed with Sam wearing her father 's mask
he 'll say some poor dumb bastard read on the Internet
that you 're the real Ghostface
and took matters into their own deluded hands .
Exactly ! That 's why it 's the perfect alibi .
And all the best lies are based on the truth .
And you 're a killer .
- Just like your father . - No , I 'm not !
Yes , you are , you motherfucker ! You killed our brother !
What are you talking about ?
You said your brother died in a car accident .
No , no , no , you sweet , dumb thing .
He died in Woodsboro ...
at the hands of your bitch sister .
You 're Richie 's family .
Yeah .
- Go ! Go ! - Now she 's finally
starting to get it .
Now ! It wasn 't until I saw that photograph
of what you 'd actually done to him that I knew .
That I knew you had to fucking die ! You had to be punished !
Along with anyone else who stands in our way .
There she is .
There 's the fucking killer .
Real great parenting job , by the way .
Shut your whore fucking mouth !
- Oh , shit . - You okay ?
Have I been a perfect dad ?
No .
Have I maybe overindulged Richie 's love of these little movies ? Yeah
maybe .
For me , they 're just a little dark .
But ...
Richie really loved them .
He loved them !
He even made a few of his own .
Did you know ? Did you know ?
So you guys think I didn 't post a holiday special .
Well , I tried to . Okay ?
I really did try .
That I could interact with .
There 's a very special bond between a father
and his first son .
Which is why I helped him build this collection .
This was ... all his ?
Yes , he 's a very passionate collector .
And he inspired others .
We had to kill those two wannabe film students because , well ...
we had to kill you first , Sam .
I put the theater in their name
then good ol ' Detective Bailey would 've just stumbled on it
but I didn 't have to because , by golly
that Gale Weathers is one hell of a journalist .
I built a tribute to my son .
Which is why this is where you have to die , Sam ...
surrounded by all the things he loved the most .
What happens next ? What after
you 're done with us , what , you just disappear ?
No ! We gotta hurry over to the hospital
and make sure Mindy and Gale don 't pull through .
Because everybody dies , Sam !
Everyone who had anything to do with the death of my son suffers and dies .
- Fuck yeah , they do ! - Yeah !
Now put on the mask .
He was ...
so pathetic .
That 's not true .
Yeah , your son ...
he was a man-baby who made his girlfriend do all the killing .
He was a strong , virile young man !
He was a limp-dick little fuck who cried before I slit his throat .
Shut the fuck up !
Sam , come on !
No !
Recognize this ?
Fuck you !
Sorry , but I kinda need this .
Fuck him up .
What are you gonna do about it , bitch ?
Oh , fuck !
Fuck !
Sam !
I 'll get help .
Be careful .
Come on .
Go get her . Get her !
- I can 't grab you . - It 's okay .
I can 't ... I can 't grab on .
I can 't grab on .
No !
I 've always wanted to stick something in you , Tara .
- Fuck you ! - Fuck you !
You guys are so fucked now !
Sam .
Sam ?
- Let me go . - No !
Yeah , let her go , Sam , come on .
- Fuck ! - Trust me .
Fuck !
You have to let me go .
Gotcha !
Now die a fucking virgin .
Looks like you 're down another brother .
Always gotta shoot them in the head .
Oh , fuck .
Hello .
Do you see your boyfriend anywhere ?
I don 't even have a boyfriend right now .
Would you like one ?
I don 't even know you and I dislike you already .
Hello , Detective Bailey . I 've got one question for you .
Oh , yeah ?
What 's that ?
What 's your favorite scary movie ?
" Favorite scary movie . "
I 'm asking because you 're in one now .
You 're in my movie .
I see you 've put on your true face , huh ?
Your birthright .
Poetic that you 're gonna die in it .
This is what you wanted , isn 't it ?
Now you know the truth , huh ?
Murder 's in your blood !
Stop fucking around and show yourself !
Be careful what you wish for .
All right , I 'm a fucking police officer .
How do you think this is gonna go , Sam ?
Who do you think they 're gonna believe , huh ?
Probably the one who 's still alive .
No ! No !
My father was a murderer .
No matter what you think
I 'm better than that .
Thank you .
But you did fuck with our family , so ...
Nice .
Thanks .
You okay ?
No .
Thank you for letting me go .
I knew you could take care of yourself .
I want to be in your life
but only as much as you want me to be .
I want you to be .
I promise you I 'm gonna get so much therapy after this .
I 'm serious .
We 're gonna get through this .
Together .
I saw that in a scary movie once .
Sam . Hey .
Two over there . Let 's go .
- Here . - Let 's go .
- Are you okay ? - Yeah .
I thought you might need some reinforcements .
And I called Mount Sinai , and Mindy and Gale are gonna be okay .
Mindy 's on her way here now . They couldn 't stop her .
Not bad , Cute Boy .
Thanks .
If you ever need me , call .
We 're all part of the same fucked-up family now .
And legacy doesn 't always have to be a bad thing .
Okay .
Hey .
It 's just Chad .
Hey , we got another one here !
Watch out , coming through .
- Oh , my God . - Chad !
Chad !
How are you alive ?
Core Fucking Four .
Sorry . You probably need that .
Oh , my God ! Are you guys okay ?
I know who the killer is ! It 's Ethan and Bailey .
And Quinn .
And Quinn ? Fuck !
Did I miss the monologue again ?
Are you okay ? Are you okay ?
You don 't look okay .
Oh , my God , we all survived . It 's a twist on a twist .
They gave me a lot of drugs by the way .
You guys should get some of these drugs .
I can 't feel anything below my shoulders .
Sam .
Coming ?
Not every movie needs a post-credit scene .